Printed Maps Printed.Maps
American Philosophical Society
Printed Maps Guide
Various Dates
Printed.Maps
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
Printed maps at the APS are not individually cataloged, but have been available as part of the guide Realms of Gold. This finding aid represents all of the printed maps listed in that guide arranged geographically. Each entry contains a sequential number as was found in the original guide beginning with entry 53. Manuscript maps are cataloged within manuscript collections and are not listed in this finding aid.
- Space
  - A chart of the zodiacal stars, used in finding the longitude at sea by the moon. And their hourly positions to the circumpolar stars, both above and below the north and south poles. By S. Dunn. London., 4 July 1772.; 53; Size of paper: 38.1 x 90.1 cm.; Colored.; S. Dunn.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Presented by Samuel Dunn, 8 October 1772.
  - [Map of the moon accompanied by an explanation of the figures and letters]. N.p.: [ca.1832]., 54; Size: 40 cm. diameter.; J. J. Littrow and Albert Richard.
    Scope and Contents note
    Enclosed in original wrapper marked: DERMOND.
    Presented by C. Nagy, 15 May 1833.
  - Sketch of the solar system for the use of schools. Printed at the Lith. Press of His Majesty the King of Oude. Lucknow: 1835., 55; Size: 75.2 x 73.9 cm.
    Presented by J. P. Engles.
  - General-Karte der sichtbaren Seite der Mondoberflaeche zugleich als übersichts-Blatt zur grössern Mondkarte von Wilh. Beer und Joh. Heinr. Mädler. Berlin: Simon Schropp et Comp.: 1837., 56; Size of paper: 59 x 48.3 cm.; E. Leidenfrost.; Wilh. Beer and Joh. Heinr. Mädler.
    Presented by A. D. Bache, 6 December 1839.
  - Celestial charts made at the Litchfield Observatory of Hamilton College, Clinton, N.Y., by C. H. F. Peters. N.p.: [ca. 1884]., 57; 20 charts.; Size of paper: 58 x 40 cm.; Original wrappers.
  - Lick Observatory atlas of the moon. N.p.: [ca. 1895]., 58; 20 plates.; Size of paper: 50.3 x 40.5 cm.
    There is also one photograph entitled: Mond-Atlas von L. Weinek.
    Provenance: Published by the gift of W.W. Law, from original negatives.
  - Egyptian chart of the heavens. Constellations of the northern hemisphere. By Lee H. McCoy. Pueblo, Colo.: Franklin Press Co.: 1911 [24 July 1911]., 59; Size of paper: 43.2 x 41 cm.; Lee H. McCoy.
    McCoy wrote that this chart of the ancient Egyptian constellations contained "but about one half" of the Egyptian constellations he had worked out and that he would like to hear from the Society about it.
    Presented by Lee H. McCoy, 3 August 1911.
  - Copernican system. N.p.: n.d., 60; Size: 19.2 x 20.3 cm.
  - [Lunar orbiter material. Missions 1-5]. U.S. National Aeronautics and Space Administration. N.d., 61
    Presented by Donald Menzel, October 1971.
- The World
  - Universalior cogniti orbis tabula ex recentibus confecta observationibus. Published for Cl. Ptolomaei Geographia. Rome: 1508., 62; Size: 40.6 x 54.1 cm.
    Facsimile. Contains facsimile autograph of John Farden.
  - Nova & accuratissima totius terrarum orbis tabula nautica variationum magneticarum index juxta observationes anno 1700. Habitas constructa per Edm. Halley. 1700. London: Vincent Brookes, Day & Son, 1870., 63; Size: 48 x 114.6 cm. [The size of the copy in the British Museum is 48 x 201/2 in.]; Edmund Halley.
    Contains autograph of G. B. Airy.
    Reproduced by photolithography, September 1870, with the permission of the Principal Librarian of the British Museum, from the copy (presumed to be of the original edition) preserved in the Library of the Museum.
    Presented by Greenwich Observatory, 6 October 1871.
  - Mappe-monde divisée en ses quatre parties. N.p. 1759., 64; Size: 15.6 x 30 cm.
  - Carte des parties principales du globe terrestre pour servir à l'histoire des deux premiers siècles depuis la création du monde. Dediée à Monseig[neu]r le Comte de Saint Florentin, ministre & secrétaire d'état, Commandeur des Ordres du Roy. Par Monsieur Luneau de Boisjermain. Paris: 1765., 65; Size: 59.8 x 82.3 cm.; H. Gravelot.; Jac. Charpentier.
    Inset: Supplement à la carte du Paradis Terrestre.
    "Premier feuille."
  - Chart of the world, according to Mercator's projection, shewing the latest discoveries of Capt. Cook. London: C. Dilly and G. Robinson: 1785. 15 June 1785., 66; Size: 37.2 x 48.6 cm.; Colored.
    Engraved for Guthrie's new system of geography.
    Contains manuscript notations for use in Carey's edition. The Transactions (Vol. 6) state that Carey presented the "Materials from which Guthrie's Geography were compiled." This is one of those maps. See: William Guthrie, The general atlas for Carey's edition of his geography improved. Philadelphia: Carey: 1795 [1 May 1795] (912.G98c).
    Presented by Mathew Carey, 18 October 1805.
  - A map of the world from the best authorities. London: C. Dilly & G. Robinson: 1785., 67; Size of plate: 30 x 54 cm.; Colored.
    Engraved for William Guthrie. Atlas to his system of geography... London: Dilly: 1785.
    Shows tracks of James Cook's voyages.
    The Transactions (Vol. 6) state that Carey presented the "Materials from which Guthrie's Geography were compiled." This is one of those maps. See: William Guthrie, The general atlas for Carey's edition of his geography improved. Philadelphia: Carey: 1795 [1 May 1795].
  - [Map of the world in two hemispheres]. Western, New World Hemisphere; and, Eastern, Old World Hemisphere. London: William Faden: 1786 [28 October 1786]., 68; Size of plate: 36.7 x 73 cm.; Colored.; William Faden.
    Purchased from the library of William Priestman, 15 July 1831.
  - A new general chart of the world, exhibiting the whole of the discoveries made by the late Capt. James Cook, F.R.S. with the track of the ships under his command. Also those of Capt. Phipps (now Lord Mulgrave) in his expedition to the North Pole. London: Wm. Faden: 1787 [1 January 1787]., 69; Size: 41.7 x 57 cm.; Colored.; William Faden.
  - A map of the world, drawn & engraved from d'Anville's two sheet map, with improvements for I. Harrison No. 115, Newgate Street. [London]: I. Harrison: 1788. 1 December 1788., 70; Size of paper: 47.6 x 78 cm.; Colored.; Neele.
    In two hemispheres.
  - [Two designs for projecting the map of the world. 1789]., 71; Size of plate: 18.8 x 27.1 cm.; Eliza Colles.
    In: Christoper Colles. The geographical ledger and systematized atlas.
  - Carte magnétique des deux hemisphères. N.p.: [ca. 1790]., 72; Size: 48.2 x 93.3 cm.
    "No. 8."
  - A chart of the world, according to Mercators projection; shewing the latest discoveries of Capt. Cook. London: [ca. 1790]., 73; Size: 36.4 x 47.2 cm.; Woodman & Mutlow.
    Showing the tracks of the Endeavour and the Resolution. Engraved for Chambers's edition of Guthrie's new system of geography.
  - To George Washington president of the United States of America this magnetic atlas or variation chart is humbly inscribed by John Churchman. Philadelphia: James Johnson: 1790. First edition. Trimmed., 74; Size of paper: 60.6 x 62.4 cm.; Colored.; John Churchman.
    In: Pam. 538.7:C47e. John Churchman, An explanation of the magnetic atlas or variation chart. Philadelphia: James Johnson: 1790. Front.
    Churchman was an American who was devoted to his own theories of the variations of the magnetic needle and other things. He had presented his scheme to the Society in 1787 and was given mild encouragement. He founded his belief on the
    hypothesis of two bodies (besides the moon) revolving round the earth, in small circles parallel to the equator; one near the north pole, and the other was near the south pole; and the needle, being wholly governed by the attraction of these magnetic satellites, will, in whatever part of the world, always rest in the plane of the circle, passing through them and the given place. [ The American Museum, Sept. 1789: p. 218].
    He persevered in his work and at the 17 September 1790 meeting his "Navigation Chart, or Magnetick Atlas" was presented. It disappeared, but another copy was given by Johann Rodolph Valltravers on 19 May 1797. The Valltravers copy is the one now at the Society.
    Wheat: 6
    Presented by the author to the Society, 17 September 1790, with a description. Another copy presented by Johann R. Valltravers, 19 May 1797.
  - Dialing. A "Universal Dial" incorporating a "terrestrial globe," indicates Africa, Europe, Asia, and America on the globe. [1792]., 74a; Scale: Diameter of the sphere = 2.8 cm.; Size: 27 x 20.6 cm.; Scot.
    In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 5, opposite p. 792.
    Wheat: 15
    Presented by Thomas Dobson, 1798.
  - Geography. Map of the world, comprehending the latest discoveries. Captain Cook's last voyage is shown with his Alaskan discoveries. Zaara or The Desert appears for the Sahara in Africa. [1792]., 74b; Scale: Diameter of sphere, 17.4 cm.; Size: 19.6 x 35.5 cm.
    In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 7, following page 662.
    Wheat: 16
  - Geography. A map of the world in three sections, describing the polar regions to the tropics in which are traced the tracts of Lord Musgrave and Captain Cook towards the North and South Poles and the torrid zone or tropical regions with the new discoveries in the South Sea. [North and south hemispheres and a belt map of the tropical regions]. [1792]., 74c; Size of plate: 23.5 x 43.5 cm.; W. Barker.
    In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 7, following p. 662.
    Wheat: 17
  - Geography. [With six diagrams, four of which show portions of the earth's surface. All the continents are shown on one or more of the hemispheres. California is shown as an island]. [1792]., 74d; Size of plate: 23.7 x 17.5 cm.
    In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 7, opposite p. 650.
    Wheat: 14
  - Die Obere oder Nördliche Halbkugel der Erde auf den Horizont von Berlin stereographisch entworfen von T. E. Bode Astronom der Königl. Pr. Acad. d. Wissensch. 1793, [and] Die Untere oder Südliche Halbkugel der Erde... [Berlin]: 1793., 75; 2 maps.; Sizes: 45.7 x 43.5 cm. and 43.5 x 43.3 cm.
  - The world from the best authorities. [Boston]: Thomas & Andrews: [ca. 1796]., [ca. 1793].; 76; Size of plate: 20.4 x 38.2 cm.; Amos Doolittle.
    Engraved for Morse's geography. [ American Universal Geography, 1, front.]
    Wheat: 19
  - A correct chart of the terraqueous globe, on which are described lines shewing the variation of the magnetic needle in the most frequented seas; originally composed in the year 1700 by the celebrated Dr. Edmund Halley; renewed by William Mountaine and James Dodson, F R S according to observations made about the year 1756. London: Laurie & Whittle: 1794 [12 May 1794]., 77; Size: 52.1 x 122 cm.; Size of paper: 55.3 x 147.9 cm.; Edmund Halley, William Mountaine, and James Dodson.
    On either side are: An account of the variation chart, and, Remarks on the variation lines &c.
  - A general chart of the globe, shewing the course of the Gulph Stream, and various tracks to and from the East Indies, China, Europe &c. [This is a chart on Mercator's projection with eight different lines lettered from "A" to "H" showing Truxtun's courses between various points. 1794]., 78; Scale: 2.5 cm. = ca. 690 mi.; Size: 45.5 x 89.4 cm.; Thomas Truxtun.
    In: Thomas Truxtun, Remarks, instructions, and examples relating to the latitude and longitude.. ., frontispiece.
    Wheat: 22
    Presented by Thomas Truxtun, 17 February 1797.
  - General chart on Mercator's projection. [1798]., 78a; Scale: 2.5 cm. = ca. 35° latitude.; Size: 17.9 x 24.9 cm.; Rollinson.
    See: John Payne, A new and complete system of universal geography, vol. 1, opposite p. v.
    Wheat: 39
  - The world from the best authorities [1798]., 78b; Size of page: 21 x 38 cm.; Rollinson.
    In: John Payne. A new and complete system of universal geography, vol. 1, frontispiece.
    Wheat: 40
  - Chart of the variation of the magnetic needle, for all the known seas comprehended within sixty degrees of latitude north and south; with a new and accurate delineation of the magnetic meridians, accompanied with suitable remarks & illustrations. By Thomas Yeates. [London]: Black, Barbury & Allen: 1817 [22 August 1817]., 79; Size: 53 x 122.8 cm.; Size of paper: 60.6 x 154.4 cm.; J. Walker.
    Contains also: Remarks historical and explanatory; Deductions and experiments made by Capt. M. Flinders relating to the variation of the magnetic needle; and Example of the aberration of the needle caused by a change in the ship's head.
    Presented by John Garnett, prior to 1818.
  - The world on Mercator's projection; revised and improved to 1818 by John Melish. Philadelphia: John Melish & Saml. Harrison: 1817 [16 October 1817]., 80; Size: 91 x 123 cm.; Colored.; John Melish.; S. Harrison and G. Murray.
    Contains statistical table of the several countries shown on the map. Contains also tracks of various explorers: James Cook; Vancouver; Furneaux; La Perouse; Clerke; Capt. Gore ( Resolution); Commander James from Bombay; Capt. Phipps, Lord Musgrave; and of certain famous ships.
    Presented by John Melish, 5 November 1819.
  - A new and authentic map of the world embracing all the recent discoveries, and exhibiting particularly the nautical researches of the most distinguished circumnavigators from the latest & best authorities with numerous corrections & additions, by H. S. Tanner, 1831. Philadelphia: Tanner: 1831., 81; Size: 89.8 x 168.5 cm.; Colored.; E. B. Dawson.; H. S. Tanner.
    Contains also: comparative lengths of the principal canals in the world, projected on a scale of 34 miles to an inch; statistics for North America, South America, West Indies; Summary of Africa, Asia, Oceania, and Europe statistics; heights of mountains; British possessions in Africa, America, Asia, Oceania; possessions of European powers in Asia, Oceania, Africa, America; vertical sections of North America, projected on uniform scales.
    Presented by Henry Schenck Tanner, 15 April 1831.
  - The world. Philadelphia: Engraved and published by W. Williams: 1842., 82; Size: 51.6 x 63.9 cm.; Colored.; William Williams.
    Insets: District of Columbia; Sandwich Islands; Map of Palestine and the Holy Land; and Map of the American Colony of Liberia.
    Contains tracks of ships of Cook, Biscoe, Furneaux, Vancouver, La Perouse; Clarke; Gore, James Waddell, Columbus, etc.
  - Colton's map of the world on Mercator's projection. New York: J. H. Colton & Co.: 1855., 83; Size: 41 x 62.4 cm.; Colored.
    Contains isothermal lines of frigid or cold, temperate, tropical and equatorial zones; and, tracks of famous explorers and ships: Cook, La Perouse, Vancouver, Furneaux, U.S.S. Vincennes, etc.
  - Maps showing the location of the diplomatic and consular offices of the United States of America. 1 March 1888. Washington: Government Printing Office: 1888., 84; 8 maps.; Size: 44.7 x 54.7 cm.; A. C. Roberts and G. Noetzel.; N. Peters, Photo-Lithographer, Washington, D.C.
    Contains index to the maps.
  - Principal transportation routes of the world. U.S. Department of Commerce and Labor, Bureau of Statistics. N.p.: [ca. 1908]., 85; Size: 57.6 x 136.3 cm.; Size of paper: 81.3 x 145 cm.; Colored.
    At bottom are distances from New York, New Orleans, San Francisco, and Port Townsend to the principal ports of the world and the principal cities of the United States.
  - [Map of the world]. Chicago: Geographical Publishing Co.: [ca. 1943]., 86; Size: 75.5 x 66 cm.; Colored.
    Contents include scenes from foreign lands and pictures of U.S. presidents to F. D. Roosevelt.
  - Terrestrial magnetism. By Colonel Edward Sabine. Physical atlas. Plate 23. London: William Blackwood & Sons: n.d., 87; Size of paper: 53 x 66.4 cm.; Colored.
    Contains seven maps of the world.
    Accompanied by a broadside which describes the plate.
    Presented by Maj. Gen. Sabine.
- Eastern Hemisphere
  - [Eastern hemisphere. A topographical map showing Europe, Africa and Asia. 1796]., 87a; Scale: 13.7 cm. diameter.; Size: 14.6 x 15.9 cm.
    In: Constantin F. C. Volney, The Ruins, opposite p. 29.
    Wheat: 29
  - Geography. [Three spheres, one of the heavens; one depicting an imaginary island; and, one showing Europe and Africa. 1792]., 87b; Sizes of spheres: Diameters of 5.7 cm.; 3.4 cm.; and 5.7 cm.; Smither.
    In: Thomas Dobson, publisher, Encyclopaedia, vol. 7, following p. 660.
    Wheat: 13
    Presented by Thomas Dobson, 1792.
- Western Hemisphere
  - A new map of the whole continent of America, divided into north and south and West Indies. Wherein are exactly described the United States of North America as well as the several European possessions according to the preliminaries of peace signed at Versailles Jan. 20, 1783. Compiled from Mr. D'Anville's maps of that continent, with the additions of the Spanish discoveries in 1775 to the north of California & corrected in the several parts belonging to Great Britain, from the original materials of Governor Pownall, M.P. London: Robert Sayer: 1786 [15 August 1786]., 88; 2 sheets.; Scale: 60½ English mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 51.7 x 119.5 cm.; Colored.; D'Anville and Governor Pownall.
    Inset: The supplement to North America containing the countries adjoining to Baffins and Hudsons Bays.
  - A new and correct map of [North and South] America, with the West India Islands. London: Robert Sayer & Co.: [ca. 1787]., 89; 2 copies.; Size: 55 x 47.2 cm.; Size of paper: 61 x 103.1 cm.; Colored.
    Insets: Port Royal Harbor, Boston Harbor, Georgia, the North Pole, and how fish are cured and dried in Newfoundland. Also, on each side, are scenes of the American Indian, chiefly of Virginian, Mexican, and Peruvian natives.
  - A new map of the whole continent of America, divided into North and South and West Indies. Wherein are exactly described the United States of North American as well as the several European possessions according to the preliminaries of peace signed at Versailles Jan. 20, 1793. Compiled from Mr. d'Anville's maps of that continent, with the addition of the Spanish discoveries in 1775 to the north of California & corrected in the several parts belonging to Great Britain, from the original materials of Governor Pownall. London: Laurie & Whittle: 1794 [12 May 1794]., 90; 2 copies.; Scale: 69½ English mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 103 x 119.7 cm.; Colored.; d'Anville and Gov. Pownall.
    Insets: Countries adjoining to Baffins and Hudsons Bays; and Possessions of various countries in North and South America.
  - America nach der zweyten Ausgabe von Arrowsmiths Weltcharte und dessen Globular Projection, nach den Berichten der Jesuiten und anderer Reisebeschreiber, und nach Raynals, Gatterers, Angaben entworfen von C. Mannert. Herausgegeben mit Kaiser. Allergl. Privil. Nürnberg: Adam Gottlieb Schreiber u. Weigel: 1796. [North and South America]., 91; Size: 52.6 x 60.8 cm.; Colored.; C. Mannert and Arrowsmith.
- The Arctic
  - [Circular map of the arctic regions]. N.p.: [ca. 1790]., 92; Size: 24 cm. diameter.
    Endorsed: Late eighteenth-century hand: North Pole.
    Contains: Mr. Hearn's "Rout" in 1771 from Fort Churchill.
    Published for William Guthrie, Atlas to his system of geography. The Transactions (vol. 6) state that Carey presented the "Materials from which Guthrie's Geography were compiled." This is one of those maps. See: William Guthrie, The general atlas for Carey's edition of his geography improved. Philadelphia: Carey: 1795 [1 May 1795].
  - Arctic Sea. Baffin Bay. Sheet 1. 1853. London: Hydrographic Office of the Admiralty. Corrected to 1855. [London]. 1855., 93; Size: 63.3 x 48.5 cm.; J. & C. Walker.
    Insets: Omenak Fiord; and Disko Bay.
    There are ten engravings of capes, inlets, islands, etc.
  - Chart exhibiting the discoveries of the Second American Grinnell Expedition in search of Sir John Franklin. Unrevised from the original material and projected on the spot. E. K. Kane. Deposited 15 November 1855., 94; Scale: 2.8 cm. = 10 mi.; Size: 89 x 56.2 cm.; E. K. Kane.; Julius Bien.
    Presented by E. K. Kane.
  - Arctic Sea. Melville Sound. Sheet II. 1856. [London]: 1856 [26 May 1856]., 95; Size: 63.7 x 49.7 cm.; J. & C. Walker.
  - Chart showing the discoveries tracks and surveys of the Arctic Exploring Expedition of 1860 and 1861. I. I. Hayes, M.D., commanding. Newly projected from revised materials discussed for the Smithsonian Institution by Charles A. Schott. Washington: 1865., 96; Scale: 1:1,200,000.; Size: 57.8 x 36.2 cm.; Charles A. Schott.; H. S. Barnard and A. Petersen.
  - The Arctic regions comprising the most recent explorations of Robert E. Peary, Fridtjov Nansen, and F. Jackson, by Prof. Angelo Heilprin. Philadelphia: Geographical Society of Philadelphia: 1897., 97; Size of page: 45 x 49.5 cm.; Angelo Heilprin and J. W. Ross.
  - Arctic Regions [showing bank ice, cold currents & warm currents]. N.p.: [ca. 1900]., 98; Size of paper: 26.9 x 23.1 cm.; Colored.
  - Polar regions Baffin Bay to Lincoln Sea, showing the recent discoveries and routes of exploration of Civil Engineer Robert E. Peary U.S.N. together with the work of earlier explorers. Based on the chart of the Hydrographic Office. Washington: 1903., 99; Size: 48.2 x 44.2 cm.; Colored.; F. B. Greene.
    To accompany Bulletin, vol. IV, no. 1, Geographical Society of Philadelphia.
    "The name United States Coast, designating the most northernly land-mass, was suggested by Commander Perry in letter, Feb. 22, 1904."
  - Physical map of the Arctic. Translated and revised by the American Geographical Society of New York from map in Andrée's Handatlas, 8th edition, 1924. Printed in Germany. Copyright, 1929, by the American Geographical Society of New York. New York: 1929., 100; Size of page: 46 x 58.6 cm.; Scale of main map: 1:20,000,000.; Colored.
    Insets: Novaya Zemlya, Jan Mayen Island, Bear Island, Ice Fiord (Spitsbergen), Spitsbergen and Bear Island, Franz Josef Land, Eastern Greenland, Bering Strait, Northernmost Greenland, Southern Greenland, and Smith Sound to Robeson Channel.
- The Antarctic
  - [Three charts of the Antarctic (South Shetland Islands) comprising chart of Edward Bransfield, press mark "Ae 1 S92," Georges Bay, press mark "Ae 1 S90," and chart of New South Britain, discovered by Capt. Smith in the brig, "Williams," the 19th. February, 1819]. Great Britain. Hydrographic Department. [London: ca. 1822]., 101; Size: Various.; Edward Bransfield and Capt. Smith.
    Presented by J. A. Edgell, August 1941.
    Photostats of the original documents in the Hydrographic Office, Great Britain.
    See: Geographical Journal, XCIV, 315 (Oct. 1939): map C, and Geographical Review, XXXI, 491 (July 1941).
  - Bathymetric map of the Antarctic (southern Atlantic, Indian, and Pacific Oceans) compiled by the American Geographical Society of New York. New York: A. Hoen & Co.: 1929., 102; Scale: 1:20,000,000.; Size: 55.3 x 60 cm.; colored, with a scale of submarine relief.
  - Map of the Antarctic, compiled by the American Geographical Society of New York. Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic expedition 1928-1929. New York: 1929., 103; Scale: 1:12,500,000.; Size: 88 x 128 cm.; Colored.
    Insets: Map of the Antarctic archipelago, showing route of Sir Hubert Wilkins's flight, 20 December 1928. Also, photographs of fiords, islands, etc.
    Presented by Isaiah Bowman, 1929.
  - Antarctica, compiled from all available sources to 1943, including the results of all American explorations from the United States Exploring Expedition, 1839-1840, to the United States Antarctic Service, 1940-1941. Washington: Hydrographic Office: 1943., 104; Scale (latitudinal): 1:11,250,000.; Size: 78 x 122 cm.; Colored.
    Azimuthal equidistant projection.
- Europe
  - L'Europe divisée en ses grands états 1759. N.p.: 1759., 105; Size: 15.9 x 19.5 cm.